We covered four types of topologies in the last four topics: star, mesh, ring, and bus.
There is one more aspect to understand about topologies: the difference between a physical topology and a logical topology.
A physical topology is the actual appearance and setup of a network.
For example, if you have a device such as a switch or a hub in the middle of a network and devices connected to it, you have a physical star network.
However, that does not mean the data flows through the network as if it were a star network. This is where the concept of a logical topology comes in.
A logical topology describes how data flows through a network.
For example, in the days of Token Ring networks, the physical setup was a star,
but data flowed through the network as if it were a ring, with a single token bouncing from device to device.
And Ethernet networks, even though usually a physical star, actually flow logically as a bus topology.
For the exam, know that there is a difference between a physical and a logical topology.